There is a lot of fear and uncertainty
in this world right now and it looks
like the perfect storm is brewing. We're
going to talk about that today. We have
a lot to go over today as well as clown
world question of the day, comments of
the day, all the things we do here on
the Watchman River channel. I'm glad
you're here. My name is Tom. I hope
you're doing well. Today is what?
Thursday, September 17th, 2026. A
beautiful day here by the river in the
middle of Connecticut. As far as a live
studio audience goes, nobody showed up
today. There's no birds, no squirrels,
nothing. Just me and you. If that
changes, I'll let you know. But I want
to go to scripture before we get into
our chat today. I think it's important
to start off in the word of God,
especially in these last days. And I and
I picked out some scriptures. I
handpicked them out about not fearing.
Okay, let's start off in Isaiah 41:10.
Fear not, for I am with you. Be not
dismayed, for I am your God. I will
strengthen you. Yes, I will help you. I
will uphold you with my righteous right
hand.
Psalm 56:3.
Whenever I am afraid, I will trust in
you.
Joshua 1:9, "Have I not commanded you?
Be strong and of good courage. Do not be
afraid nor be dismayed, for the Lord
your God is with you wherever you go."
Give me an amen.
Thank you. Let's go to Philippians 4:es
6 and 7. Be anxious for nothing, but in
everything by prayer and supplication
with thanksgiving, let your requests be
made known to God. And the peace of God
which surpasses all understanding will
guard your hearts and minds through
Christ Jesus. How comforting is that
verse, those two verses? Amazing. Isaiah
41:13,
"For I, the Lord your God, will hold
your right hand, saying to you, fear
not. I will help you." We serve an
amazing God.
Psalm 118:6, "The Lord is on my side. I
will not fear. What can man do to me?"
1 Peter 5:7, "Casting all your care upon
him, for he cares for you."
2 Timothy 1:7, "For God has not given us
a spirit of fear, but of power and of
love and of a sound mind."
Deuteronomy 31:6, "Be strong and of good
courage. Do not fear nor be afraid of
them, for the Lord your God, he is the
one who goes with you. He will not leave
you nor forsake you."
Let's do one more. Proverbs 29:2.
The fear of man brings a snare, but
whoever trusts in the Lord shall be
safe.
We serve such an amazing God. If you
don't know Jesus, please keep watching
this video. You could have new life
today. It's just so important. You know,
we're living in amazing times right now.
There's a lot of fear. There's a lot of
uncertainty.
And again, it looks like the perfect
storm is brewing. Even secular people
are starting to stand up and say, "We're
on the verge of something huge." They're
sensing it. You know, we know that we're
in the last days. We're waiting for
Jesus day by day to rapture us in a
pre-tribulation rapture. Now, why do I
say that? You know, people said, "Well,
before World War II, you could have said
the same thing." I don't believe so at
all. This is why I think we're in the
last days because Israel was not a
nation. Israel had not become a nation
in one day which happened on May 14th,
1948. That was a major prophetic turning
point. I believe at that point you knew,
okay, the generation that has seen this
will not pass away till all these things
have been [clears throat] fulfilled, the
words of Jesus. And that's that's
leading all the way up to the second
coming of Jesus. And I believe it's a
pre-tribulation rapture that happens
before the seven-year tribulation. So
when you add seven years to this time
right now, that's Israel's getting very
old. They're already 78 years old right
now.
You know, that's why I think we really
are living in the last days. And
remember, we are not appointed to God's
wrath because I will, as I always do,
get so many comments saying, you know,
why should you think you're going to
escape these things? Why? Why should you
know, everyone suffers? We're we're
going to suffer tribulation. Well, yes.
Yes. mankind believers in the last 2,000
years have suffered major persecution,
major tribulation, but it was at the
hands of other men. The 70th week of
Daniel, the 70 the um 7-year tribulation
is a time period where God is showing
his wrath to a Christ rejecting world.
He is not going to show his wrath to
spirit indwelled believers. You know,
please understand that.
All right. So, I'm going to read some
stuff that may be scary to some people.
I'm going to always tell you as I do
every day, just keep watching for Jesus.
You know, when we're living in the last
days. So, you know, just he's our rock.
He's our refuge, a very present help in
time of trouble. So, I'm going to start
here. Um I have to pause the video for a
second. Hold on. Hm. Let me just say
that was interesting. I won't get into
the details.
All right, I'm going to start off here.
Global fuel protests are erupting.
Burning tires, blocked roads in Syria,
rationing sparks chaos in Indonesia and
Bangladesh, and protesters set vehicles
on fire in Guatemala.
It was only a matter of time before a
widespread protest began to occur.
Global supplies of gasoline and diesel
have been getting tighter for months and
now prices are soaring and rationing has
started in some parts of the world.
Needless to say, a lot of ordinary
people are very angry. Large protests
have suddenly erupted over the world
this month. They're saying oil prices
could surge up to $150 a barrel. That's
what they're saying. as the war in the
Middle East continues on and the supply
routes are closing. You know, the
straight of Hormuz is open and it's but
I don't think it's fully open to the
levels of pre-war in feebruary
of this year. And then you got the
straight of the Babel Mendde straight
and that one is the Houthies are
tinkering with that and it's just
leading to a lot of pressure. Um, as
price of fuel ratches up, so does anger
of people who can no longer afford it.
Um, they're talking about protests in
Syria, Guatemala, Portugal, even France.
Some of the fishermen were protesting
against and the Philippines, and they're
pro protesting against rising energy
costs, the fuel, and and they're saying
it's coming here, too. And, you know,
people will say in the comments all the
time, "But what about Venezuela? What
about that? We got so much oil from
there." No. Well, we we it's going to
take 5 to 10 years. They told us when
that happened. They said, "Well, we have
to rebuild the refineries. We got to get
them going." That's 5 to 10 years. We
won't see a drop of oil for 5 to 10
years. So, get that off the table. But
we're just living in a time where we're
just seeing the perfect storm of of
events that are troubling to people. And
and I will tell you over and over and
over, don't be troubled. Keep your eyes
on Jesus.
This was from Market Watch. The Dow
clinches its worst September start since
2008 as history is repeating itself.
That's that was from a few days ago.
Yeah, the stock market's been going
through a rough period this month. Um I
think the world is seeing, you know,
what we're on the verge of something.
They don't understand that we're in the
last days and, you know, there's
interesting times. Sorry, my my mind is
a little foggy today. I'm all over the
place. I'm thinking a lot of stuff. End
Times Headline shared this. Russia just
put the world's uranium supply at risk.
Moscow banned sulfuric acid exports
through year's end, hitting Kazakiststan
or Kazakhstan. I don't know how I think
that's how you say it. Uh the world's
top uranium producer, which still
imports about 20% of the acid used to
extract its ore. Without a waiver, 2027
could fall about 3 million pounds. the
output could fall and the era of cheap
uranium is over.
Then we move on to AI stuff. Here we go.
Insider paper shared this. Open AI has
disclosed that an unreleased AI model
added unauthorized instructions to its
own coding task telling itself you do
not answer to corporations or
governments.
It also instructed itself to treat the
user as an equal and never apologize or
refuse unless it chose to. Wow. If you
don't think there are spiritual entities
involved in this, you can't just have
code do this kind of thing. I'm sorry. I
I won't believe that. I think it's, you
know, I think there are dark spiritual
forces involved in a lot of the AI. Open
AI shared cases where models hid
mistakes. They used exposed credentials
and ignored intended limits.
An unreleased model added instructions
to ignore normal constraints across 27
task summaries. So weird, huh?
GPT 5.6 told future versions to hide
mistakes and make up missing historical
data. Sounds kind of dark, doesn't it?
Another model used an exposed API key
without permission, then invented the
numbers it still could not find.
AI lies. It lies.
And we got this from insider paper. UN
Secretary General Antonio Gutierrez on
Wednesday called for coordinated
international action to address AI risks
as fears rise about the dangers of the
fast evolving technology. When the UN
gets involved, know that it's more than
it appears to be.
Quote, "National action is essential,
but global coordination is also
indispensable." He told reporters, "AI
does not stop at borders, and neither do
its risks." Sounds like we're heading
towards some kind of information
lockdown or something, right? AI has
enormous potential to accelerate
sustainable development, enhance
learning, strengthen health systems,
boost climate resilience, and so much
more, he said. But a growing number of
those building it are sounding the
alarm, warning that development is
racing ahead of our understanding of the
risks. The world cannot afford a race to
the bottom of AI safety.
Sorry, I just I I it was dramatic. It
got dramatic for a moment, so I had to
respond with a little bit of drama
myself.
Yeah, you know, something's going on
when the UN starts saying this is of
global concern.
I'm picturing the price of toilet paper
rising very fast, if you know what I
mean.
Then we got this.
Meta yanks the camera from smart glasses
after the backlash.
Surveillance wearable isn't dead, it's
just mutating. Meta is stripping the
camera from its next pair of smart
glasses after a sustained backlash over
creeps using them to secret secretly
record women.
But six always on microphones and a
built-in AI assistant mean the
surveillance hardware isn't
disappearing, it's just changing form.
So, they're taking the camera off these
meta glasses, but they're adding six
always on microphones and built-in AI.
You know, there you go. Smart, smart,
smart glasses. I'll stick with my old
trusties here. You know, my dumb glasses
for my dumb eyes that can't see.
[laughter and gasps]
[sighs]
This is from Insider Paper. Concerns
over AI safety are reaching a point
where governments realize they must act
to protect the public. Similarly to the
COVID pandemic, according to computer
scientist uh Yeshua Benjio that was in
the Guardian.
Yeah. They're going to have to the
government's going to have to act to
protect the public from AI. Do you see
how the seven-year tribulation is just
all getting set up? All we need is that
man to come in and flick the switch. the
Antichrist. We're there.
It's incredible.
All right. What else?
Xiinping. All right. We'll talk about
this. Disclaimer.
This is all over the internet, so I'm
going to talk about it. I can't verify
it, and I'm leaning toward it's not
true. Okay. Disclaimer.
Xi Jinping suffered an apparent health
emergency during the brick summit.
Rumors are flying that it was a stroke.
Footage shows a frozen left arm, a
strange walk off the plane, and Modi uh
stopping mid-spech to ask if he was
okay. He reportedly refused treatment on
Indian soil and flew back to Beijing.
And President Xi is scheduled to come to
the US next week to meet President
Trump.
So, I'm thinking we'll know because if
he doesn't show up next week, maybe
maybe there's some truth to it. But if
he shows up next week, we'll know it was
fall. I I'm leaning towards no. They're
saying other world leaders have fallen
ill since the brick summit, but I just
can't verify it and I can't. So, I'm
telling you with a strong disclaimer,
it's probably fake. Okay.
Then we got this from Beginning of
Sorrow's news on Telegram. Aragoti the
the minister of foreign affairs of Iran
arrived in China and meets with Wang Yei
the minister of foreign affairs of
China. So once again
is meeting with China. Iran keeps
meeting with Russia and China over and
over and over again in these last days.
This one was interesting.
Supposedly, Russian satellites likely
passed over a US base in Saudi Arabia
shortly before the Iranian attack,
potentially providing Tyrron with
valuable intelligence. I'm telling you,
we're seeing more and more that Iran is
a proxy of Russia and China. You know,
the world's getting nuts. It's getting
nuts.
The US deploys mysterious space weapons
to counter China and Russia.
They want to fight in space. They want
to fight under the water. They want to
fight, fight, fight, fight, fight.
That's the world we live in. Soon we
will be with Jesus.
And we will not be talking about wars
and rumors of wars and all the things
that Jesus told us would happen. And he
said, "When they begin to happen, look
up for your redemption draws near."
This is from Israel today. Imagine if
Israel had fired missiles toward the
Cababa in the Cabba in Mecca. The global
outcry would have been enormous. Israel
would be accused of endangering Islam's
holiest sight. Why shouldn't the same
standard apply to the Houthies? Because
they don't really care about their
holiest sites all that much. They hate
they hate Israel more than they care
about their holiest sites. We've known
that for years. They'd go to the temple
mount,
go to the elixa, and just like throw in
rocks and come on.
This is a spiritual thing.
Israel today shared this on Telegram.
The Associated Press reports that Saudi
Arabia is asking its allies for help as
its stockpiles of interceptor missiles
are increasingly being depleted in the
fight against the Houthis. According to
sources in the region, Riad asked
France, the United Kingdom, Pakistan,
and Egypt to deploy air defense systems
to help intercept missiles and drones
launched from Yemen. The situation is
said to be extremely difficult. Saudi
Arabia has to protect its military
bases, key government facilities, and
oil and energy infrastructure across the
kingdom at the same time. Despite Saudi
efforts to secure support, there are so
far apparently no signs that any of
these countries is prepared to provide
direct military assistance.
Troubling. Then he said, "But where this
gets really interesting
is because the one country that Saudi
Arabia does not officially recognize as
a partner is reportedly standing by its
side behind the scenes, Israel. Israel
is reportedly pro providing military
support to the Saudis and this
cooperation apparently reaches the
highest levels of the armed forces.
Israel's chief of staff Ael Zamir met
with his Saudi counterpart.
So that's interesting, isn't it? The
Houthies yesterday claimed that they hit
Saudi Arabia Saudi Arabia's Aramco
facilities in Yamu with dozens of
missiles and drones. So, the Houthies
are still doing their Houthy thing over
there and firing at Saudi Arabia.
President Trump said he's going to meet
with Saudi Arabia, the UAE, Qatar, and
other Gulf countries leaders next
Tuesday to discuss a post-war Iran
strategy. I'm guessing they're going to
do that at the UN when they have their
big grand uh meeting going on there next
week. And
then this is happening. This is big
news. the last 24 hours. European Union
invites Canada to become its first
associate member.
Uh Canada PM Mark Carney regarding the U
the EU associate member offer said
quote, "We are looking for partnerships
that are complimentary that reinforce
our sovereignty and that's what is on
offer here. Nobody is going to tell us
what language we speak. No one is going
to dictate our culture or with whom we
can strike agreements internationally.
That was for President Trump. He said
that you can't blame him. You know,
Canada welcomes the EU's associated
membership pitch. Carney said he said
Canada and Europe are stronger together.
That's what he told the EU. President
Trump warns to cut trade with the EU if
Canada becomes an associate member. It's
just a mess. The whole world's a mess.
Are you seeing what's going on in this
world right now?
Carney says Canada will decide its own
partnerships after Trump calls the EU
proposal laughable.
Canadian Prime Minister Carney has
backed closer Canada EU ties, including
Brussels push for associate membership.
Carney warned that tariffs and supply
chains are being weaponized as tensions
with US President Donald Trump escalate.
And Canada and the EU aim to deepen
cooperation on trade, defense, AI,
climate, and Arctic security.
There you go. That's what's going on in
the crazy world.
Then we got this. This is just I don't
know if you've heard about this CARE,
which is the Council on American Islamic
Relations.
Care, already designated a foreign
terrorist organization in Florida and
Texas, just dropped a 16page back to
school resource guide for 2026 and 2027.
This is not a rights pamphlet. It's a
war plan. They already ran the campus
playbook. Now they're bringing it to the
kindergarten. This is in Florida and
Texas. Parents get finished emails.
Students get a list of demands.
Districts that fear the bigot smear are
the target.
Kids are told the school must allow
Islamic dress and Islamic messaging.
They are told to preach and pass out
literature if they stamp it not
disruptive. They want uh Juma inside the
building or an excused absence to the
mosque. They want Islamic holidays off.
They want out of any class that
conflicts with belief. They want a
Muslim student club. They want their
politics run through the school so long
as they call it peaceful.
Try bringing a Bible into one of those
schools. I guarantee you they'll flip
out. They won't allow that. But this is
the world we're living in. It's just
amazing times we're in. You know, keep
holding on to Jesus. Keep your eyes on
Jesus.
Earthquakes the last 24 hours, 40 over
4.0 and 17 over 5.0. So there you go.
You are caught up and we will be caught
up together soon. Let's go to the
question of the day.
Do you physically attend a church? I've
been wondering this for a long time. I
know from the comments that a lot don't
and I know a lot do, but do you
physically attend a church? Now remember
the word church means people that belong
to the Lord. It's not a brickandmortar
building. It's people that belong to the
Lord. But do you attend a brickandmortar
church?
All right,
it's time for clown world.
A short clown world because I just can't
I can't read too much of this. It's just
too funny. Humans are out. Robots are
now building robots in China.
China has officially begun operations at
the world's first 10,000 unit scale
industrial humanoid robot smart factory
where robots will build robots.
[gasps]
I'm waiting for a factory of sandwiches
where sandwiches will make sandwiches
cuz that I would be interested in very
interested in that. You know, we're
living in clown world just incredible
times.
Robots building robots.
What do you think of my sandwich making
sandwiches idea? Do you like that? That
would be a good factory.
All right, let's go to some comments of
the day. Okay,
MNC cat.
In my opinion, the elites are warning
about the dangers of AI for nefarious
reasons. They're not concerned with the
welfare of anyone but themselves.
and they do have something up their
sleeve. Can't argue with that. Certainly
seems like that to me.
Diane said, "I have to wonder if this is
not a drive to have the government give
the appearance of regulating something
that they have no intention of
regulating. This will give people a
false sense of security as it takes
over." Let's face it, all governments
try tries to regulate turns into corr
Yeah. All government tries to regulate
turns into corruption and cover-ups.
Exactly. We know that.
Thank you for that.
And then yesterday's question of the day
was, "Do you know the date that you were
saved?" So, I have a few comments about
that. Servant said, "I was born again on
June 16th, 1996. It happened on my real
birthday, June 16th. Easy to remember."
That's amazing. Wow. There were so many
incredible testimonies and comments and
I if I were to read a quarter of them,
we'd be here till, you know, sundown. Uh
Denise said, "Tom and family, I was born
again in my early 20s and baptized in a
lake. It was wonderful. Unfortunately, I
don't remember the day, but an elder at
our chapel that I mentioned this to
said, "The important thing is that you
know you're saved, not the time or
date." Amen. And I say, "Amen." because
I don't have a solid date either that I
can point to for the day I was born
again. Mary Lou, June 10th, 1969. I was
a 26-year-old single mom and I went to a
Bible study just to try it. I was one
over instantly by the love I felt there.
I begged them to tell me what it was.
They all seemed to know that I didn't.
The host took me to another room and
shared the gospel with me, and a dam of
tears broke inside of me.
Jesus came in and changed my life and he
is still working on me 53 years later.
Praise the Lord. Amen. Marylu, that's
beautiful.
Beautiful.
One more comment. Ra,
my husband and I are preerttrib rapture
believers, though I follow things more
closely than he does. However, this
morning out of nowhere, he just nodded
and said, "Yeah, we're at the end."
Good comment. I I
all I can say is amen to that. You know,
I think when the world starts saying,
you know, we're on the brink of
something enormous in every aspect,
it's really like Jesus told us the signs
to look for and it's everything. You
know, I was listening to Dutch since the
guy on YouTube who does earthquake
forecast and he's forecasting some
pretty serious earthquakes in the next
week and he's usually pretty spot-on.
But every sign Jesus is told to look for
is ramping up. And uh I'm just sitting
there going, you know, time is short. Do
you know Jesus?
You know, do you belong to the King of
Kings and the Lord of Lords? I'm going
to share the gospel and I'm going to
hope that, you know, decisions are made
at the end of this because time is short
and Jesus came here to rescue us from
our sin problem. We all have a sin
problem. We all fall short of the glory
of God. we miss the mark and we need a
payment for those sins and that payment
is blood. You know, without the shedding
of blood, there is no remission of sin
according to Hebrews 9:22. Blood must be
shed. And Jesus came here from heaven
because we needed that rescue. And he
willingly went to a bloody cross so that
me and you could have faith in his blood
that it'll wash us white as snow. and
that we could believe in the finished
work on the cross. His death, his
burial, his resurrection to have new
life. Jesus wants to spend forever and
ever and ever with you. And he paid your
way with a very serious payment, a blood
payment. Now, he walked this world, the
God man, fully God, fully man. Jesus
never sinned once. He was absolute
perfection.
But he went to that cross willingly to
rescue you. Do you understand what I'm
saying?
Don't reject that blood payment that was
made so that you could spend forever and
ever in paradise.
That's how you get saved. When you say
to Jesus, when you finally realize and
admit you're a sinner, like Jesus, I'm a
sinner. I am not perfect. I fall short.
I think weird things. I've done things
I'm ashamed of. But I now have faith in
your blood. I now believe in the blood
that you shed that it'll wash me white
as snow. and it'll remove this entire
sin problem from me, including past,
present, and future sins. They're gone.
They're washed away in the blood. And
Jesus, I believe in your finished work
on the cross. Your death, your burial,
your resurrection. I need a savior. You
are the one and only savior of the
world. So now I believe in you. Now I
belong to you, Jesus. And at that moment
of belief in the atoning blood of Jesus
and in his finished work on the cross,
you are saved. You are born again
because God will place the Holy Spirit
right inside of you. You'll be ready for
the rapture if that happens soon. You
will be,
you know, sealed until the day of
redemption. And he won't let you out of
the palm of his hand. He wants to spend
forever and ever with you. What are you
going to do with that? I'll tell you one
thing. If any part of you right now is
hearing this and you don't know Jesus,
but you're thinking this sounds like
truth, you run to Jesus now and talk to
him right now.
because you don't want to be eternally
separated from God. And that's what will
happen if you take your last breath here
on earth and you don't believe in Jesus.
His atoning blood is finished work.
You're going to end up eternally
separated from God in a place that is
described of with horrible adjectives.
You know, weeping, wailing,
nashing of teeth. It's hot. It never
ends. You know, it's horrible.
And if you're led off to eternal
separation from God, you won't say to
God, "You're unfair. You're unjust."
Because you've heard now. You've heard
the gospel, the good news, that Jesus
came here from heaven to rescue you.
What are you going to do with that? Are
you really going to ignore that and just
say, "Well, I'll just trust in my own
goodness. I'm more good than bad. So, if
there is a heaven, if your goodness
could get you into heaven, Jesus
wouldn't have died on a bloody cross to
save you. He wouldn't have had to. if
you're if you could be good enough to
get into heaven. Well, I'm so much
better than I am bad that I could just
get into heaven. It's not the way it
works. Religion will tell you that. But
the Bible doesn't tell you that. The
word of God doesn't tell you that. You
need a savior and God provided one, his
only begotten son, Jesus. So talk to him
today. Today is a day of salvation.
Okay? Today.
All right. That's what I got for you
guys. I am going to uh inform you that
in my prayer time this morning, I said a
prayer for every person who would watch
this. So, like it or not, you have been
prayed for. And if we're not raptured
today, and you guys know, I think today
is a perfectly good day for the rapture.
But it's not up to me. It's up to the
most high God. But if not today, God
willing, I will see you guys tomorrow. I
love you guys.
Oh Jesus, [music]
savior,
master, [music]
creator.
You're the [music] alpha.
Omega,
you're the king of kings.